

# Dexter Crago

# Full Stack Software Engineer

My Personal Website

in LinkedIn 🔘 GitHub

dexter18crago@gmail.com

Hello! I'm Dexter, a full stack software engineer with a strong grasp of programming and code design fundamentals, experience building 30+ projects from scratch, and a strong drive to continue learning and improving my skills. Please feel free to check out my personal website of to see some of my work and learn more about me and how I can start adding value to your team right away. I look forward to hearing from you soon!

#### Education

### **Full Stack Software Engineering,** The Odin Project

#### Aug 2023 - May 2024

- Created 30+ projects from scratch
- Creating frontends with HTML, CSS, JS, and React
- Creating backends with NodeJS and ExpressJS
- Managing MongoDB databases with Mongoose ODM
- Tests with Jest and authentication with PassportJS
- Version control with Git and sending data with JSON
- Creating and consuming REST APIs
- Fundamental data structures and algorithms
- Agile software development workflow
- Writing clean, efficient, and maintainable code that follows industry best practices and coding standards

#### **Bachelor of Science,** Montana State University

#### Aug 2018 – May 2023

- Strong logical reasoning and analysis skills
- Able to easily break down large problems
- Great at communicating complex technical concepts to both technical and non-technical audiences
- Using a testing mindset to pinpoint issues

# Volunteering

# **Morning Star Elementary School,** *Tech Club Leader* Feb 2022 - May 2022

• Teaching elementary students technology concepts

# **Montana Indian Ministries,** Summer Camp Leader

#### Jun 2015 – present

• Managing and guiding 50+ camp counselors

## </> Skills

HTML • CSS • JavaScript • Git VCS •

React.is • Jest • JSON • REST APIs •

Node.js • Express.js • NoSQL • JWT •

MongoDB • Mongoose ODM • Passport.js

#### Professional Experience

#### **Stevensville High School,** *Science Teacher*

#### Jan 2023 – Apr 2023

- Managed 100+ students across a variety of subjects
- Time management, organization, self-discipline
- Critical and creative thinking skills
- Conflict resolution skills
- Conducted, analyzed, and presented research

#### Montana Club, Server

#### Jun 2015 - Mar 2021

- Increased sales from \$500 to \$1000/day in one year
- Worked both in the front and in the back to better understand the whole operation
- Trusted with closing out registers containing \$1000+
- Trained junior co-workers

#### **City Life Community Center,** Youth Worker

#### Jun 2018 – Jun 2020

- Working closely with a team to coordinate trips and events for 20+ students
- Fully engaged in professional development
- Constantly considering how to better serve students
- Adaptable, teachable, and self-directed